<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Detroit Zoo</string>
    <string name="Detroit_Zoo">The Detroit Zoo is located about 2 miles (3.2 km) north of the
                                Detroit city limits at the intersection of Woodward Avenue, 10 Mile
                                Road, and Interstate 696 in Royal Oak and Huntington Woods,
                                Michigan, United States. The Detroit Zoological Society (DZS),
                                a non-profit organization, operates both the Detroit Zoo and
                                the Belle Isle Nature Center, located in the city of Detroit.
                                The Detroit Zoo is one of Michigan\'s largest family attractions,
                                hosting more than 1.5 million visitors annually. Situated on 125
                                acres of naturalistic exhibits, it provides a natural habitat for
                                more than 2,000 animals representing 245 species. The Detroit Zoo
                                was the first zoo in the United States to use barless exhibits
                                extensively.
    </string>
    <string name="go_to_categories">Go To Categories</string>
    <string name="detroit_zoo">Detroit_Zoo</string>
    <string name="categories">Categories</string>

    <!-- +-+-+-+ Zoo Animals +-+-+-+ -->

    <!-- +-+-+ Amphibians +-+-+ -->
    <string name="amphibians">Amphibians</string>

    <string name="gopher_frog">Dusky gopher frog</string>
    <string name="gopher_frog_dsc">The dusky gopher frog is medium-sized with a wart-covered
                                    body that is black, brown or gray with dark spots. It has
                                    ridges along its back. Typically found in southern Mississippi,
                                    this frog prefers to be in stump holes or burrows. This species
                                    has an estimated population of less than 150 in the wild. The
                                    decline is mainly due to habitat destruction. The dusky gopher
                                    frog is one of the top 100 most endangered species in the
                                    world, according to the International Union for the
                                    Conservation of Nature.</string>

    <string name="japanese_salamander">Japanese giant salamander</string>
    <string name="japanese_salamander_dsc">The second largest salamander in the world, it can
                                            reach just over 4 feet long and weigh up to 88 pounds.
                                            Its skin is a mixture of gray, black and white, and is
                                            heavily wrinkled. This species has an elongated body,
                                            a long broad tail and two pairs of legs that are
                                            similar in size. The eyes are small and positioned
                                            on top of the broad, flat head.</string>

    <string name="mantella_frog">Mantella frog</string>
    <string name="mantella_frog_dsc">The mantella frog is a part of a large family of frogs that
                                        vary in color from yellow to red to orange. This very small
                                        frog has aposematic colorations, which means its bright and
                                        contrasting colors indicate toxins to potential predators.
                                        In the wild, it uses the adhesive pads on its toes to stick
                                        to trees and leaves. The male frog has a smaller body
                                        compared to the female, which has a more angular body.
                                        Like many amphibians, the mantella frog spends almost
                                        all of its time on land.</string>

    <!-- +-+-+ Birds +-+-+ -->
    <string name="birds">Birds</string>

    <string name="african_pygmy_goose">African pygmy goose</string>
    <string name="african_pygmy_goose_dsc">The male African pygmy goose is mostly white, with
                                            spots of green.  The female has a white face with gray
                                            spots and black under the eyes.  Both the male and
                                            female have a red tint on its belly with green marking
                                            on the rest of its body. It has a short bill, a
                                            rounded head and short legs.</string>

    <string name="bald_eagle">Bald eagle</string>
    <string name="bald_eagle_dsc">The adult bald eagle has a white head and tail with a dark brown
                                    body and wings. Their legs and bills are bright yellow. Young
                                    birds attain adult coloring in about five years.</string>

    <string name="gentoo_penguin">Gentoo penguin</string>
    <string name="gentoo_penguin_dsc">The gentoo is recognized by the white stripe extending across
                                        its head and its bright red-orange bill. The bird also has
                                        paddle-shaped, peach-colored feet and fine feathers that
                                        help it glide easily and quickly through the water. It is
                                        the third-largest penguin species, after the king and
                                        emperor penguins.</string>

    <!-- +-+-+ Invertebrates +-+-+ -->
    <string name="invertebrates">Invertebrates</string>

    <string name="butterfly">Butterfly</string>
    <string name="butterfly_dsc">The butterfly has its skeleton on the outside of its body, called
                                    an exoskeleton. This protects the butterfly and keeps water
                                    inside its body so it doesn’t dry out.  The butterfly spends
                                    much of its lifespan as egg, caterpillar and chrysalis, and
                                    will only be in its winged adult form for a short period –
                                    typically less than a month.</string>

    <!-- +-+-+ Mammals +-+-+ -->
    <string name="mammals">Mammals</string>

    <string name="arctic_fox">Arctic fox</string>
    <string name="arctic_fox_dsc">The arctic fox’s body is short and compact to help keep it warm
                                    during frigid temperatures. Its feet are covered in fur to
                                    provide traction on the rough tundra terrain. During the
                                    winter, its fur color is white and during the summer it turns
                                    to a brownish-gray, which allows it to remain camouflaged
                                    year round.</string>

    <string name="american_beaver">American beaver</string>
    <string name="american_beaver_dsc">The largest rodent in North America has a lustrous reddish-
                                        or blackish-brown, waterproof fur coat, webbed hind feet
                                        and a broad, flat, scaly tail that is roughly 10 inches
                                        long. The beaver has a disproportionately large skull and
                                        four powerful, orange-colored teeth – two upper and two
                                        lower incisors – that are used to gnaw on tree bark. Its
                                        small, round ears can close to keep water out.</string>

    <string name="miniature_donkey">Miniature donkey</string>
    <string name="miniature_donkey_dsc">The miniature donkey resembles a horse and is characterized
                                        by its large head, long ears and cow-like tail. It can be
                                        black, white and all shades of brown and gray, but the most
                                        common color is a mousy-gray called “gray dun”. It can be
                                        spotted, speckled or striped and its hair can be straight,
                                        curly, short and wiry or long and wooly. A solid-color
                                        donkey has a dark dorsal stripe from mane to tail and a
                                        dark stripe across its shoulders. It has an erect mane and
                                        lacks the forelock of a horse.</string>

    <string name="horse">Thoroughbred horse</string>
    <string name="horse_dsc">The Thoroughbred horse is best known for being used in horse racing.
                                It is most often bay, chestnut, seal brown, black or gray in color.
                                The Thoroughbred horse tends to be high-spirited, fast and very
                                athletic.</string>

    <string name="otter">North American river otter</string>
    <string name="otter_dsc">The river otter’s fur color ranges from white to gray, brown and
                                black. The aquatic mammal has a long, cylindrical, streamlined body
                                that sports short, dense, waterproof fur, profuse whiskers and
                                short legs. The otter’s strong tail and webbed feet help propel
                                it through the water, which makes it a great swimmer.
                                Once abundant in U.S. and Canadian rivers, lakes and coastal
                                areas, river otter populations have suffered significant declines
                                as a result of fur trapping, water pollution, habitat destruction,
                                pesticides and other threats.</string>

    <!-- +-+-+ Mammals +-+-+ -->
    <string name="reptiles">Reptiles</string>

    <string name="african_spurred_tortoise">African spurred tortoise</string>
    <string name="african_spurred_tortoise_dsc">The African spurred tortoise is well camouflaged by
                                                its overall sandy coloration. It has thick golden
                                                to yellow-brown skin and a brownish carapace. The
                                                broad, oval carapace displays prominent serrations
                                                at the front and back margins and noticeable growth
                                                rings on each scute, which become marked with age.
                                                Large overlapping scales cover the front surface of
                                                the forelimbs, while the hind surface of the thigh
                                                bears two or three large conical spurs, from which
                                                it earns its name.</string>

    <string name="chinese_alligator">Chinese alligator</string>
    <string name="chinese_alligator_dsc">The Chinese alligator is dark green to yellowish gray with
                                            black spotting on the lower jaw.  It is much smaller
                                            than its American counterpart, with a slightly upturned
                                            and more tapered snout as well as bony plates on its
                                            upper eyelids.   Its long, thick tail is its primary
                                            source of force while moving through the water.  The
                                            Chinese alligator also has bony plates, or osteoderms,
                                            covering its back and underside of the body to act as
                                            armor.  Juveniles appear very similar to adults, but
                                            have distinctive yellow bands on their bodies which
                                            fade as they mature.</string>

    <string name="rattlesnake">Mexican lance-headed rattlesnake</string>
    <string name="rattlesnake_dsc">The dark blotched pattern of the snake is very distinctive
                                    compared to other rattlesnakes. The blotches are often oval or
                                    elongated at the front part of the body and become more
                                    circular toward mid-body. Four to seven crossbands are usually
                                    at the tail. Typically it has a tan, brown, gray or sometimes
                                    white underside.</string>
    <string name="animal_picture">Animal Picture</string>

</resources>
