<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Week2Day4</string>
    <string name="week_2_day_4">Week 2 Day 4</string>

    <!-- +-+-+-+ Biographies. +-+-+-+ -->
    <string name="anna">Anna Henrietta</string>
    <string name="anna_Als">Anarietta, Henarietta, Lady Duchess</string>
    <string name="anna_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="anna_Nat">Toussaint</string>
    <string name="anna_Prf">Duchess of Toussaint</string>
    <string name="anna_Bio">Anna Henrietta was the ruling duchess of Toussaint, and beloved by all
                            her people. She ruled the country with her husband Raymund until he
                            died in 1265, two years before Geralt and his friends arrived in
                            Toussaint, after which she ruled as the sole monarch.
                            Her official, protocol title is "Her Enlightened Ladyship",
                            unofficially "Her Grace" and in more casual matters outside the court
                            she is to be referred to as "Lady Duchess." However, the Chamberlain
                            and Marshal of the Court Sebastian Le Goff strongly advised Geralt to
                            address her as "Your Grace" at all times. She is known to a select few
                            by the shorter name, Anarietta. </string>

    <string name="calanthe">Calanthe Fiona Riannon</string>
    <string name="calanthe_Als">Ard Rhena, Lioness of Cintra, Modron</string>
    <string name="calanthe_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="calanthe_Nat">Cintra</string>
    <string name="calanthe_Prf">Queen of Cintra</string>
    <string name="calanthe_Bio">Calanthe Fiona Riannon of Cintra, known also as the "Lioness of
                                Cintra" and "Ard Rhena" ("High Queen" in Elder Speech), was a
                                queen of Cintra, the mother of Pavetta, and grandmother of Ciri.
                                Her nephew, Crach an Craite, called her "Modron". She was known
                                for her bravery and beauty. </string>

    <string name="cerys">Cerys an Craite</string>
    <string name="cerys_Als">Sparrowhawk</string>
    <string name="cerys_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="cerys_Nat">Skellige</string>
    <string name="cerys_Prf">Queen of Skellige Isles</string>
    <string name="cerys_Bio">Cerys an Craite, aka "Sparrowhawk", was the daughter of Crach an
                                Craite, and Hjalmar\'s younger sister. The young woman was a
                                courageous islander like her father and had inherited all his
                                stubbornness. She was very self-confident and always ready to
                                prove she could fulfill any task as good as a man, which caused
                                her and Hjalmar to have a constant, but good-natured, rivalry.
                                However, unlike her brother, she appeared more levelheaded,
                                choosing to investigate and think things through first before
                                jumping to conclusions.</string>

    <string name="ciri">Cirilla Fiona Elen Riannon</string>
    <string name="ciri_Als">Ciri, Lion Cub of Cintra, Falka, Zireael, Swallow, Ashen one</string>
    <string name="ciri_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="ciri_Nat">Cintra</string>
    <string name="ciri_Prf">Witcheress and Empress of Nilfgaard</string>
    <string name="ciri_Bio">Cirilla Fiona Elen Riannon (also known as Ciri), was born in 1253,
                            and most likely during the Belleteyn holiday. She was the sole princess
                            of Cintra, the daughter of Pavetta and Emhyr var Emreis (who was using
                            the alias "Duny" at the time) as well as Queen Calanthe\'s
                            granddaughter.
                            After Geralt of Rivia helped lift Duny\'s curse, Duny asked what
                            reward the witcher would like and Geralt proclaimed the Law of
                            Surprise, as it turned out Pavetta was pregnant with Ciri, unbeknownst
                            to Duny. Six years to the day after the child's birth, Geralt went
                            back to Cintra for her, but did not take her with him to Kaer Morhen
                            at that time. In fact, he didn't even lay eyes on her and only spoke
                            with Calanthe, who divulged no information to him, not even the
                            child's gender.
                            While she was still an infant, Ciri's parents were both lost in a
                            storm at sea and were presumed dead. She spent her youth in Cintra
                            and Skellige under the care of her grandmother and her uncle. </string>

    <string name="aval">Crevan Espane aep Caomhan Macha</string>
    <string name="aval_Als">Avallac\'h, Fox, The Mysterious Elf</string>
    <string name="aval_Rce">Elf</string>
    <string name="aval_Nat">Tir Na Lia</string>
    <string name="aval_Prf">Aen Saevherne</string>
    <string name="aval_Bio">Crevan Espane aep Caomhan Macha, also known as Avallac\'h (pronounced
                            "Ah-vah-lahk"), was an elf and Aen Saevherne who had the ability of
                            traveling between the worlds of the Aen Elle and Aen Seidhe. He met
                            Geralt and told the witcher about a prophecy connected with Ciri. He
                            was nicknamed \'Fox\' by the unicorns.
                            Lara Dorren originally intended to marry him, before she fell in love
                            with Cregennan of Lod.
                            He was the one who brought Ciri to the Aen Elle king Auberon, promising
                            Ciri that she would be allowed to return to her world, if she conceived
                            a child with the king. Eredin however claimed that Avallac'h was
                            lying. </string>

    <string name="emhy">Emhyr var Emreis</string>
    <string name="emhy_Als">Duny, Urcheon of Erlenwald</string>
    <string name="emhy_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="emhy_Nat">Nilfgaard</string>
    <string name="emhy_Prf">Imperator of Nilfgaard</string>
    <string name="emhy_Bio">Emhyr var Emreis, Deithwen Addan yn Carn aep Morvudd (in the
                            Nilfgaardian dialect - The White Flame Dancing on the Barrows of his
                            Enemies), also known to a few under his alias as Duny, the Urcheon of
                            Erlenwald (Polish: Jeż z Erlenwaldu) was the Imperator of the
                            Nilfgaardian Empire, Lord of Metinna, Ebbing, Gemmera, Sovereign of
                            Nazair, Vicovaro and, after marrying Cirilla, King of Cintra, from
                            1257 when he overthrew the Usurper who murdered his father, Fergus var
                            Emreis, until his death sometime in the late 13th century.
                            His rule of Nilfgaard was highly aggressive, often pursuing
                            expansionist policies similar to those of his predecessors. This led
                            to the outbreak of two wars against the Northern Kingdoms, both of
                            which he lost. Emhyr var Emreis was an intelligent and brilliant ruler.
                            He chose his people well and crushed many plots against him. He was
                            ruthless toward traitors and moved towards his goals with great
                            determination.
                            He was publicly favorable to the Elder Race, in stark contrast to
                            monarchs of the North. </string>

    <string name="regis">Emiel Regis Rohellec Terzieff-Godefroy</string>
    <string name="regis_Als">Regis</string>
    <string name="regis_Rce">Higher Vampire</string>
    <string name="regis_Nat">Toussaint</string>
    <string name="regis_Prf">Barber-Surgeon</string>
    <string name="regis_Bio">Emiel Regis Rohellec Terzieff-Godefroy, better known simply as Regis,
                                was a very powerful higher vampire, and more than four hundred
                                years old when he first met Geralt of Rivia. He was the
                                barber-surgeon of Dillingen but surprisingly intellectual for
                                one in such a profession. </string>

    <string name="eredin">Eredin Bréacc Glas</string>
    <string name="eredin_Als">Sparrowhawk</string>
    <string name="eredin_Rce">Elf</string>
    <string name="eredin_Nat">Tir na Lia</string>
    <string name="eredin_Prf">King of the Wild-Hunt</string>
    <string name="eredin_Bio">Eredin Bréacc Glas, also dubbed "Sparrowhawk" by the unicorns, was
                                an Aen Elle elf and commander of an elven cavalry known as the Wild
                                Hunt. As its leader, he was known to most as the King of the Wild
                                Hunt. Eredin was a high ranking general in his world until he
                                killed the king and became his successor. </string>

    <string name="geralt">Geralt of Rivia</string>
    <string name="geralt_Als">White Wolf, Gwynbleidd, White One, Butcher of Blaviken,
                                Ravix of Fourhorn</string>
    <string name="geralt_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="geralt_Nat">Kaedwen</string>
    <string name="geralt_Prf">Witcher</string>
    <string name="geralt_Bio">Geralt of Rivia is a witcher and the main protagonist of the Witcher
                                series by Andrzej Sapkowski and its adaptations, including The
                                Witcher (PC), The Witcher 2: Assassins of Kings, and The Witcher
                                3: Wild Hunt video games. Like all witchers, Geralt is a monster
                                hunter for hire. He possesses superhuman abilities and is a master
                                swordsman. During the Trial of the Grasses, Geralt exhibited
                                unusual tolerance for the mutagens that grant witchers their
                                abilities. Accordingly, Geralt was subjected to further
                                experimental mutagens which rendered his hair white and may have
                                given him greater speed, strength, and stamina than his fellow
                                witchers.
                                Geralt is also known as Gwynbleidd, meaning "White Wolf" in
                                Elder Speech. He was given this alias by the dryads, and is also
                                called the Butcher of Blaviken after an unfortunate incident in
                                that town.
                                Despite his title, Geralt does not hail from the city of Rivia.
                                After being left with the witchers by his mother, Visenna, he grew
                                up in their keep of Kaer Morhen in the realm of Kaedwen. In the
                                interest of appearing more trustworthy to potential clients,
                                young witchers were encouraged to make up surnames for themselves
                                by master Vesemir. As his first choice, Geralt chose "Geralt
                                Roger Eric du Haute-Bellegarde", but this choice was dismissed
                                by Vesemir as silly and pretentious, so "Geralt" was all that
                                remained of his chosen name. "Of Rivia" was a more practical
                                alternative and Geralt even went so far as to adopt a Rivian
                                accent to appear more authentic.
                                Later, Queen Meve of Lyria knighted him for his valour in the
                                Battle for the Bridge on the Yaruga conferring on him the formal
                                title "of Rivia", which amused him. He, therefore, became a true
                                knight of Lyria, only to lose the title soon after for
                                departing. </string>

    <string name="jaskier">Julian Alfred Pankratz</string>
    <string name="jaskier_Als">Dandelion, Jaskier, The Crimson Avenger</string>
    <string name="jaskier_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="jaskier_Nat">Redania</string>
    <string name="jaskier_Prf">Bard</string>
    <string name="jaskier_Bio">Julian Alfred Pankratz, Viscount de Lettenhove, better known as
                                Dandelion, was a poet, minstrel, bard, and close friend of Geralt
                                of Rivia.</string>

    <string name="triss">Triss Merigold</string>
    <string name="triss_Als">Fourteenth of the Hill, Merigold the Fearless</string>
    <string name="triss_Rce">Human</string>
    <string name="triss_Nat">Temeria</string>
    <string name="triss_Prf">Advisor, Mage</string>
    <string name="triss_Bio">Triss Merigold of Maribor was a legendary Temerian sorceress of the
                                13th century. Called Fourteenth of the Hill by her contemporaries
                                because she was erroneously thought to have been killed during the
                                Battle of Sodden Hill, she passed into history as Merigold the
                                Fearless. A member of King Foltest\'s royal council along with
                                Fercart and Keira Metz, as well as a founding member of the Lodge
                                of Sorceresses, she was involved in politics for most of her life.
                                She was friends with Yennefer and the witcher Geralt of Rivia,
                                but also unhappily in love with the latter.[1] Triss took care of
                                Ciri at Kaer Morhen for some time and is like an older sister to
                                her. It was through her intervention that Ciri was not subjected
                                to harmful hormone changes at Kaer Morhen, stripping her of her
                                secondary gender traits.
                                She was a skilled healer and carried with her many magical potions,
                                but she never uses them on herself because ironically, she was
                                allergic to potions. She was also quite a powerful mage, certainly
                                when it counted most. She wore an amulet - sapphire overlaid with
                                silver. </string>
    <string name="race">Race: </string>
    <string name="nationality">Nationality: </string>
    <string name="name">Name:</string>
    <string name="profession">Profession:</string>
    <string name="biography">Biography:</string>
    <string name="alias_es">Alias(es):</string>

</resources>
